Guide to the Time Inc. Sports Illustrated for Kids Records 1987-1996 MS 3009-RG 55
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Sports Illustrated for Kids Records
1987-1996
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 55
1 Linear feet in 1 record carton and 1 flat box
Sports Illustrated for Kids (SIFK) was developed by Sports Illustrated staff starting around 1987 and launched in January 1989. Records primarily document the development of SIFK and include prospectuses, circulation plans, marketing plans, advertising plans, story list ideas, kids survey results, and a copy of the first issue.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers. Unreformatted digital material in the collection is not accessible.
Materials in this collection are stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Historical Note
Sports Illustrated for Kids (SIFK) was developed by Sports Illustrated staff starting around 1987. The first issue launched in January 1989. While in development, it was called "SI Junior." The early prospectus for SIFK states, "Sports Illustrated is planning a monthly sports magazine for boys and girls aged 9 through 12. This publication will have the editorial quality-the interesting stores, the exciting photographs-you would expect from SI, but it will be done to suit the tastes, interests and expectations of younger readers." "The editorial purpose of the magazine will be to emphasize the enjoyment that exists in all sports..."
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Scope and Contents
Sports Illustrated for Kids (SIFK) Records comprise material marked "to be filed" by the Time Inc. Library and primarily document the development of SIFK. The material comes from several members of Sports Illustrated (SI) / SIFK staff including first Managing Editor John Papanek (previously SI Senior Editor), first General Manager Gretchen Teichgraeber (previously SI Magazine Development Director), and first Marketing Director Susan Alexander (previously SI Research Director). Records include prospectuses, circulation plans, marketing plans, advertising plans, story list ideas, kids survey results, and a copy of the first issue.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically with arrangement imposed by the archivist.
American periodicals -- History; Corporations -- History.; Corporation records.; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Organization files.; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives.; Time, inc. -- History.
- Early Ideas, circa 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 4101, Folder 1)
- History, 1987-1991 (Offsite-box 4101, Folder 2)
- Information Master Binder: Contents, circa 1993 (Offsite-box 4101, Folder 3)
- Information Master Binder: Cover, circa 193 (Offsite-box 4147, Folder 1)
- Issues, 1989, 1996 (Offsite-box 4101, Folder 4)
- Launch Presentation, 1988 (Offsite-box 4101, Folder 5)
- Marketing Materials, circa 1988 (Offsite-box 4101, Folder 6)
- Multimedia Encyclopedia, 1994 (Offsite-box 4101, Folder 7)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes digital material.
  Materials include one unopened box of The Everything You Want to Know About Sports Encyclopedia containing a CD-ROM.
- Pre-Launch (Name Research), 1987 (Offsite-box 4101, Folder 8-9)
- Prospectus and Early Ideas, 1988-1994 (Offsite-box 4101, Folder 10)
- Strategic Plan, 1996 (Offsite-box 4101, Folder 11-12)